Sync and fixed by Neeboo
There's a legend that precedes
the dawn of our civilization.
A vile god, so large and so powerful
that it consumed entire planets as fuel.
Few believed such a thing could be true
until the day we saw Unicron with our own eyes.
But he didn't just come for our planet,
he wanted our greatest technology.
The Transwarp Key.
And he sent his most
powerful henchmen to collect it.
Scourge.
More enemies are landing.
We won't be safe for long.
Do we have the key?
You must take it.
Keep it hidden.
So that it never falls
into the hands of Unicron.
But, Ape Link, we can fight.
No. Protecting our
transwarp key is all that matters.
Go. Use it to escape.
What will you do?
I'll hold him off.
I'll use some time.
Then I'm staying with you.
This is my fight. Listen...
If Unicron were to get the key, he could
open a portal through time and space
with no end to the
worlds he could destroy.
It is now your time
to lead the Maximals,
Optimus Primal.
So you're this planet's great warrior.
You have such a beautiful world.
Filled with an abundance of life.
Savory.
My master grows hungry.
Give me the Transwarp Key
and he will spare your home.
We'd rather die
than let him breach other planets.
So be it.
Benefits of serving the almighty Unicron.
They never learn.
Too late, Scourge.
Your master will be
trapped in this galaxy forever.
No.
His sacrifice will be our oath
to preserve the key,
no matter the cost.
You let them slip away
with the Transwarp Key.
Scour the universe and find
where the Maximals have gone.
When you acquire the key,
use it to bring me to you.
Yes, my lord.
Once I have the key
I alone will reign supreme.
All right, baby, come on.
All right, show me the money.
Here we go.
Yo, Sonic, breakfast already up?
I ain't your butler, Chris.
Come on, man.
I'm calling himself the Airways.
It's Tails.
Oh, my bad.
Christopher Diaz
from 974 Wilson Avenue,
apartment 2C, Brooklyn.
No real name. They are listen.
Ain't no secret government
agency's worried about us Tails.
Now get your mind out of here while it's hot.
We still got that going for him.
Here, I earned this for you.
-I already earned it.
Like you cooked those eggs?
What you mean? It's just seasoned.
Oh, come on.
Come here, bro.
I can't get past Bowser.
Well, good morning to you, too.
Drink this and take your medicine, all of it.
Hey, are you sure you can take off?
Yeah, hospital's on the way.
You all got time?
That lady, that administrator is there,
and she mentions a bill.
Just... Tell her we're handling it.
I will.
And after today,
I'll be able to help out more.
Good luck on the interview.
Don't forget to laugh at all the jokes.
White people love that shit.
-Ma, language.
Okay.
Remember I have class tonight,
so I'll be home late. Lo quiero.
I love you. All right,
then we gotta get into the city.
Hey, hold up, hold up.
Your hands hurting again?
No, it's nothing.
Let me see.
Chris.
It's swollen.
Sickle cells must be
blocking the blood flow again.
How long has this been going on?
-Couple days.
Yo, look, I told you.
You gotta tell me these things.
You fighting this alone
or we fighting it together?
Together.
On team?
On team.
Two foot ten,
two foot stop touching everything.
Oh hell, no.
Chris, what I tell you
about letting your man
come out the crib looking like a
whole square? -There's so much I could do.
Yeah whatever bro, look. Here.
My dog.
When you gonna let me put your skills
to work and get you some real money?
It says the dude can't even afford cable.
-Hit the guy who done went away.
I choose not to purchase cable.
It's my own personal way.
The protest of vampiric
nature and modern day capitalism.
Take a look with that
interview with that dusty suit.
Look at this. -Hey guys.
That's a good one, but the inkling stars?
Most of the armor diamonds are new.
Thank you so much.
Thank you, thank you for being here.
Intern, intern, I paged you three times.
Why didn't you call me?
Okay, well, I figured if I stopped the call,
they would make me later.
The police are here.
They busted an art auction.
The owner claims that everything is authentic,
but they want a second opinion.
All right.
The Da Vinci sketch is legit.
The paint is a copy.
Well, one's at the
National Gallery in London.
Roman Vaz.
Valuable, but you are not gonna retire.
Sinners Greek curse tablet,
it would be expensive, but it's a fake.
How can you tell?
See the speller? Roman.
Doesn't even show up in our era.
Got it.
Officers, I figured it out.
So, the Da Vinci, that is...
Now where did you come from?
What are you?
It's pretty neat, right? -Yes.
Where is it from?
-They just discovered it in Sudan.
The boys say it's Horus,
5th millennia BC Nubian.
This symbol is definitely not hieroglyphic.
Well, if it's as exotic as it looks,
I'm gonna get a feature in Minerva.
Julian.
Okay, team. Let's do it.
Okay, what are the rules?
Girls before hoes.
Don't be a problem.
Don't go looking for a problem.
-Or else we're gonna have a problem.
I know, I know.
Okay, I'll be back in a little bit.
Mr. Diaz?
Hey, I know we're a little behind on the bill...
-Three months behind and until your account is current
you can't bring your brother here.
I've told you that. -I'm gonna fix it.
I just need a little more time.
-You can always take him to the ER.
Well, they won't see him in the ER unless
he's critical. -Mr. Diaz.. -He's 11 years old.
Come on crispy, we got to go.
What happened?
-Tell you later, man, right?
Come on, let's get out of here.
Hey, you sit here.
Don't move.
After a conference with Simpson's attorney,
Howard Weitzman, Simpson... -Can I help you?
Yes. Hey, I'm here for an interview
with the head of security, Mr. Bishop.
I'm Noah Diaz.
It's been canceled.
-No, it hasn't been a mistake.
Then write for Mr. Bishop.
Mr. Bishop. -Hey! Hey!
It's okay, Walker.
-It's me, Noah Diaz.
Sir, I think your boy back there is confused.
He said our interview is canceled. -Because it is.
Wait, why? On the phone
you said I was perfect for the job.
You said this was just a formality.
It was until your old
commanding officer called me back.
Said you were brave,
an expert Comtech, but unreliable.
Couldn't trust you.
Your head was always somewhere else.
Sir, I can't explain all of that. I had
some responsibilities at home. My brother...
You had responsibility to the United States Army.
Mr. Bishop, sir, I'm a hard worker. Okay?
I just...
I just really need a break.
Listen, I can't have someone like you
mess up what I built.
Someone like me?
You don't know anything about me!
I know you don't know
how to be part of a team.
My God.
Hey, look, Superman
went on a bunch of interviews
before he got his job
on the Daily Planet.
Man, he never gave up.
-I'm not Superman, Chris.
Life ain't a comment, though.
-I'm just saying, you'll get the next one.
Yo, there is no next one.
No one's coming to save us.
We're alone in this.
Hey, man, I'm sorry.
Sorry. -No, it's not.
None of this is.
Know what?
Come on.
Go ahead, bro.
Let's head upstairs.
I'll be right there, all right?
So what was you talking about earlier?
Hey yo, you want one?
No, I don't want any candy.
You gotta relax, B.
Your energy is really
affecting my chi, and I get it.
I was nervous my first time too,
but you might wanna do some
breathing exercises or something. Look at me.
My man, my man, my man, my man.
It's just, I ain't done this before.
I know that,
but them rich cats in there,
they give a ton of paper to charities
every year to make themselves feel better.
Hell, if you look at it from a
holistic perspective, we doing them a favor.
Hey, yo, you're well!
Yo, B, stop!
What are you doing?
This ain't about to affect their pockets at all.
And it's about to be easy as hell.
-So why you ain't the one going in there doing it?
Because, Papito, I'm the mastermind.
Now, come on, put this in your ear.
My man, you serious?
Yo, is that even clean?
It's the fourth quarter.
We got about 10 seconds left
on the clock, and you got the rock.
That's too much. -Well, hey, man!
Don't slam the...
Okay, I'm off to my fundraiser.
What do you think?
It's nice.
Can I, can I have something by you?
Hey.
So I've been doing some research,
and I don't think that the statuette is Horace.
As a matter of fact, I'm sure it's not.
The boys dated it around 5000 BC, right?
But the Nubians,
they never even had contact
with the Egyptians
until 600 years after that.
The symbol's not hieroglyphic.
I don't even think it's
from that part of the world.
I think it might be Aztec or Inca.
It's not some Egyptian god.
It's something else.
Interesting.
Get those pressed, okay?
Yeah.
There you go.
Let that breath fill you up. In, out.
Knees, stop talking.
OK, all right. I get it.
You don't like to chit chat back
and forth, but I got something for you.
We got a Robin mixtape?
No. I got a liberating mixtape.
You're feeling that, huh?
Yeah, whatever.
Aight, there shouldn't be nobody
in this part of the building.
We shouldn't be able
to just walk right on in.
Strike one, that's the mind.
This place is packed.
Hey, Walter, everybody is divine.
Just act like you own the place.
Hey, what's up, brother?
Good to see you again.
Try not to look suspicious.
Here you go, here you go.
Sorry, sorry. That's you, bro.
Nice glasses.
I didn't know you had glasses.
What are you doing, making friends?
Everything good?
We're here to mix.
Hey.
Let's see what you really are.
Now my man said it's tucked in the back.
Been there a couple weeks.
It's like the grayish car
with like a... -Little stripe.
Alright now just like
brother Rick showed you.
Down the window.
A little wibble.
Feel that snag and...
Yeah.
Now we makin' money.
All right, talk to me, homie.
I'm in.
It's quite a bit.
Stop, stop! Please.
No, no, no, no.
I'm gonna lose my job.
Stefan, Nynobean.
This cannot be.
Calling all Autobots! Calling all Autobots!
Yippee ki-yay!
Prime, this is RC. I have a visual.
What am I looking at?
A way home.
Calling all Autobots! Calling all Autobots!
What am I doing?
-Wel, the cops is clear out here,
so whenever you want to slide
that thing on out, you good.
I can't. I can't.
Like you can't drive stick
or something? -No, it's just...
it ain't no thief.
Are you having an existential crisis now?
The deadline for that was
when I offered you Twizzlers.
This is an emergency.
Can you hear me, Mirage?
Roll out.
Yo, who the hell was that? -It's the
radio bro. This car is bugging. I'm out.
Hey!
Shit. Oh shit.
Hey you!
Get out of the car!
I'm trying. The car started by itself.
I promise. Look, it's not working.
Get out now!
Hold up, wait! What you doing?
Nos?
Breathe, breathe, breathe!
Now let's talk to your manifestation.
Dude, the car is driving by itself!
Noah, you good?
-I don't know what's going on!
It won't stop!
Stop, stop! Why don't you listening?
But you might want to slow down.
-It's not me. The car is possessed.
No, no, no.
You just saw the adrenaline hot.
Let's do some of them breathing exercises.
Yo, I don't need no breathing exercises.
The car's driving by itself.
No. No.
No, Reek, what do we do?
No, I cannot hear you.
Reek! -No, I can't.
No, we did not.
No, you did not just leave me.
Pull over! -Help me!
Drive. Drive, drive, drive!
The bridge. The bridge,
take the Williamsburg!
I got a 10-37 in progress, silver Porsche.
How serious, man?
Oh, nah. Oh, nah.
Help me with something, please!
Oh! Yo, nah!
Nah, nah, nah!
Come in, come in!
Can you hear me, Mirage? -What?
Four us.
Yo, yo, slow down! Slow down!
Woo hoo hoo!
That felt good!
Get some oil pumping, you know!
Damn!
I haven't cooped up forever, dude.
I can't tell you how old it gets.
Mirage, stay hidden!
Mirage, don't draw any attention to yourself!
Mirage, big is just a movie!
You'll never be a real boy!
But that was fun, man. You're fun, dude.
Alright. This is probably a lot for you, huh?
Back off! -Hey, whoa, whoa,
what's with the aggression.
Well, I thought after the car chase
we were boys. You gonna hit me?
Maybe.
Just like that?
Tough guy. I like that. I like it a lot.
What are you? Some sort
of possessed car or something?
Nah, that's not real man. I'm an alien.
Like, like E.T.?
E.T., the little ugly guy
in the basket? Look at this face!
The name's Mirage.
Come on, give me a little,
give me a little, give me a little tap.
Give me a little tap.
There you go, now we're friends.
Oh great, the gang's here.
They're more like you?
Like me?
Nah, but be cool so they
don't crush you. -What?
Yeah, I'd put that
pipe down if I were you.
Well, well.
Soon we got here.
Mirage, what have you done?
You brought a human here?
Optimus, hey! Looking good, man!
Wait a second, are those new ribs?
You were told to stay hidden.
Right, right. Crazy coincidence.
When you called all Optimus-like...
Autobots roll out!
This guy was already in the car,
but he's cool, so it's cool. Cool?
Not cool.
Who are you, human?
I'm nobody. I ain't even seen nothing.
I'm not even seeing anything right now.
RC.
Private Noah Diaz, US Army.
Multiple commendations,
a wizard with electronics.
He's a soldier.
He does not look like a soldier.
I mean, you're looking
pretty rough yourself.
Sorry, sir.
I will deal with your mistake later.
- Okay, the energy surge we felt
was in the 4000 yadahertz range,
which is undetectable to humans.
I've reconstructed
the source from the energy echoes.
I cannot believe it.
It exists and it is here.
What the hell am I looking at?
The transwock key. It was thought
to be lost thousands of years ago.
It was once used to open space-time portals
to energon rich planets throughout the universe.
You mean energon-rich planets like...
Cybertron.
After seven long years stranded on Earth,
we finally found a way home.
Where did that catch you, Lake?
Okay, so where is this tran...
Transwarp Key? -Thank you.
It's in the new museum on Ellis Island.
Let's blow it up!
Get the hell out of that.
No, we can't just go in blasting and steal it, B.
The humans will hunt us down.
What we need is a quiet way in.
Ooh, how about him?
No.
What? Come on, man.
He could slip in right
through one of them little doors.
Grab the key, leave a
nice IOU, and peace out.
He's perfect.
What?
No, it is a bad idea.
I agree with big man.
So, it's been real, y'all?
What? -Time out.
No, no, I know. I know who to relax.
Let me just talk to my guy real quick.
Yo, don't leave me with these tight asses, bro.
We make a great team.
This is a waste of time.
Look, I'm not bringing in
a museum for some space robots.
But what about for friendship?
Uh, uh, or, or, or...
What about for cash?
You help us get this key
so we can get off this rock.
No offense.
Love the neighborhood and all.
And then I let you sell me.
Lambo?
Ferrari?
Elite?
Look, you get paid, and then I'll split.
So all I gotta do is walk in and out.
All you gotta do, we'll take care of the rest.
Cross my spark and hope to die.
Wow, that was corny when I said it out loud.
And what about the big man, Optimal or whatever?
You let me worry about him.
Cool?
Ah, got him, easy baby, woo!
So y'all are robots that transform into cars,
even though you're from way out in space.
But now there's this key
that opens a portal back to your home?
Oh, and you know this because
there's a beacon light in the sky
that I can't see because I'm human.
You say that like it's weird.
It's super weird.
You know what's weird?
Marky Mark is leaving the funky bunch.
I heard he's just gonna pursue acting now.
That's crazy.
-What? How does that even...
What a world.
Whatever, man.
I'm just trying to collect this money
and get your angry-ass boss
off Earth before he blows a gasket.
Don't take it personal.
He just misses home.
And I think he blamed
himself for us getting stuck here.
Earth was supposed
to be a pit stop, you know?
A place for us to regroup
and rejoin the war back home.
Prime feels like it's his
fault we've been stranded here.
Like, he has to fix it all on his own.
All right, team, heads up.
There's security up ahead.
Nice.
This is going to be fun, man.
No, bro, you need to switch it up.
You need to turn into a helicopter
or a speedboat or something.
I got something way better than that.
Good call.
I do not like this plan.
Yeah, Mirage isn't really known for being quiet.
At least Mirage is one of us.
We should not be relying on a human.
They are my friends.
I know one was good to you,
Bee, but this is not our world.
The humans will always protect what is theirs.
We can only trust our own kind.
You can't handle the truth!
I do not want you going to
that drive-in theater anymore.
Nightbird, search the island.
Finally, the hunt draws to a close.
Hello?
Fudge.
Are you okay?
Yo, you okay?
I didn't think anyone was in here.
That's it.
Who are you?
I'm a janitor.
So get ready!
No, no, no, you don't have to do that.
It's not what it looks like. -It looks
like you're trying to steal museum property.
Okay, it's a little what it looks like.
Hey! Hey, hey,
it doesn't belong to you anywhere.
Just stop, just...
Hey, hey, relax, relax.
And let me explain, it belongs to...
To these...
To these giant robots from space.
Really?
Look, I'm gonna need that. Stop!
Damn! -Damn?
Hey, hey, hey!
What's going on here? Don't move!
Man, it's about time you showed up!
The key.
You were telling the truth.
Yeah, but those ones aren't with me.
Rip the flesh from their
bones and bring me the key.
It's yours.
Guys, we got company!
Autobots, protect the key!
Not so fast!
Oh, they're flying now?
Who the hell are these guys?
Impossible.
I enjoy that look of confusion
when an inferior being
meets a higher power.
What the hell are those things?
Are you okay?
Hey, stop follow me.
-I'm not follow you.
I'm just escaping
in the same direction.
We're moving.
Keeping strong.
You put that dust in your arm.
It's sick of losing.
I don't give it what you want.
Just as...
Run!
Go, go!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Get her out!
How is that?
Thanks.
Scourge, I have eyes on the key.
Prime, I don't think
we can hold these guys...
No! No!
Oh my god! Put me down!
No!
Whoa, I'm so scared.
Oh, cool, you're still alive.
Get the key!
Noah, get out of here!
Get off me! I hate spiders!
Go, go, go!
Go! Get out of here!
Leaving some soon?
Come on, go!
Vicky!
Enough of these games,
I'll get it myself.
Not on my watch.
Don't be frightened, humans.
This'll all be over soon.
And you call yourself a prime?
Primus would be ashamed.
I'm tired of little things
getting in my way.
Bee!
Look back to my chapter.
No!
Bee...
Now to add a prime to my collection.
Maximus. -Good.
Maybe we'll get a real fight.
Now we got what we came for.
This cannot be.
We must go now. Come with me.
This is my fault.
It should have been me.
I'm sorry for your loss.
No offense lady,
but who are you again?
My name is air razor.
I am a maximal, a warrior
from both your past and future.
Oh, right. That tracks. Yeah.
We fled our whole planet
on the eve of this destruction.
We sought refuge and hit here on earth.
Alright so you're a Maximal, y'all are Autobots,
what was those things that attacked us earlier?
Terraconts. Servants of a dark hungry god
who feeds on entire worlds to sustain himself.
Unicron. -So you're saying this
thing Unicron eats planets to survive?
Yes. And heimbues his servants like scourge
with dark energy which makes him all but invincible.
He is entirely beholden to Unicron.
Through his power, he possesses Scourge's soul.
Awaken my dark master.
Rise.
My hunger is killing me.
What have you found?
Salvation.
The galaxy will once again
be yours to feast on my master.
I should have gotten the key myself.
I should have known better than to rely on humans.
Hold up, were you blaming me?
After you conveniently left out
the part about a planet eating monster?
Because of you, Unicron will now use
the key to consume every planet in the universe.
Including my home world.
He doesn't have the key.
At least not all of it.
You fool!
This is only half the key.
Freeze the Maximals!
They must have split it!
Excuses!
Complete the key or else you will wish
you had died with the rest of your planet.
We broke the key into two pieces for
safe keeping, then splintered and went into hiding.
I do not know where the other half is.
For all I know, I am the last of our kind.
This in Peru?
How do you know that?
It's the symbols on the stone.
They were only ever recorded
in one other place in the world.
The Inca Temple of the Sun in Cusco.
It's one of the oldest buildings
in the Western Hemisphere.
I'm guessing that that
can't be a coincidence.
If you can track those symbols
to Peru, so can the Terracons.
We need to get there before they do.
And then kill Scourge and take
his piece to complete the key.
Now hold up. Hold up.
You wanna find this other key and
deliver it to the guy that just kicked your asses?
The transwarp key is our only way home.
If this dude gets a hold of that thing,
it's game over for Earth.
Our families, everybody.
I'm going.
Out of the question.
No offense.
But I'm not trusting my home
to a guy who couldn't even protect his.
It's my planet.
I'm going.
What about you?
Me?
What is your name?
Elena.
Will you lead us to this temple?
Chance to stop the end of the world.
Actually,
you'll be saving two worlds.
Yeah.
Yo, is that you, Sonic?
What you doing up, Tails?
I can't sleep.
It's too hot?
You playing that game too much.
Give it a rest
so your hand can take a break.
I'm gonna beat it.
My money's on you, bro.
We don't quit.
Come on, get some sleep, all right?
Yo listen, I gotta head out for a while.
I don't know when I'm gonna be back.
Why?
Oh shit!
Oh no, oh no!
Stop, stop, please, turn it off!
What are you doing?
I told you to sit tight!
Is not enough? I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
-Is that a robot? -No, no. Go back to bed.
Shut it off!
I had hot wires, so I messed up my life.
-I got the bat. -Give me that.
Did he say bat?
-You gonna wake up Mom.
I know you're a robot.
Chris!
Yo! You scratched my paint!
What are you doing?
Man, they didn't treat E.T. like this.
You know this thing?
-Yeah, we're just work friends.
Work friends? You've been inside me.
Look, the thing I told you I have
to go do is wear him and his crew.
We're trying to stop the end of the world.
The world's ending?
No, maybe. Sixty, forty.
You know I'm not gonna let that happen.
But that's why I have to leave.
I'll go get my things.
Tough kid. -What? No.
Whoa, whoa. Hold on, hold on.
You're not coming. -Why?
You need someone to watch your back.
It's too dangerous, Chris.
And I need you to stay here
and take care of Mom.
'Cause you might not come back.
Hey, robot.
Me? What's up?
Watch out for my brother. Okay?
You got it, little man.
Nah, I'm serious.
If he gets hurt, I'm coming after you.
Don't worry. I got Noah's back.
I promise.
Hong-Ting?
Hong-Ting.
Kid's got heart.
Wu Tang is in the building, baby!
Way to be incognito.
Aw, come on, Prime. Smile a little bit.
It won't hurt.
Let me see that underbite.
All right.
So what kind of jet we taking to Peru?
Or is it a plane? Either one's fine.
I just need first class, okay?
'Cause I got long-ass legs.
Well, he is a plane.
No, no, no.
Don't tell me we're flying on...
Oh no!
My lads! I am Stratosphere,
Lord of the Skies!
Yeah, I'm walking to Peru.
Oh my gosh.
But I think you're moving too fast.
Sorry.
I sing when I get nervous.
It usually calms me down.
First time flying?
And it's my first time leaving New York.
Oh, my god.
Oh, god.
So the Bronx, huh?
Brooklyn, all right?
East New York all day.
I'm from Bushwick. -Really?
Me and my dad,
we used to go to this pizza spot
down on Nickafauka and Green.
Tony's Pizza?
Wow.
Tell me about your pops.
What was he like?
-He was a cabbie for 40 years.
Smartest guy you ever met.
They could talk to you about anything.
History, science, cricket.
Cricket?
He ain't never even go to college either.
I used to always say,
if you keep your eyes and your ears open,
life will show you
everything you need to know.
So that's why you say yes to all of this?
I figured if he is somewhere watching,
then seeing his daughter
do something crazy like this,
would definitely make him proud.
Do you really think
this key thing's in Peru?
I think so.
The evidence lines up.
You know, if it is,
when we get our hands on it,
you know we gotta destroy it.
What?
It can't unite the key
without both pieces.
No key, no Unicron,
no Earth-game Eden.
Yeah, but didn't they kick you?
We gotta think about us.
All you gotta do is find it,
and I'll take care of the rest.
Do you think an energon
infusion could bring him back?
Perhaps if we could
get him back to Cybertron.
I never should have
taken us so far from home.
Wow, wheeljack needs
to fix that power steering.
Sorry I'm late.
I was taking in a harmonious moment
between a serene butterfly
and an unruffled caterpillar.
Substrung queasy.
Yo, oh yeah, papa, where you from?
Cybertron.
So where'd you get that accent?
Accent? What accent?
You know what I'm saying?
I'm just, I'm saying it's cool.
Like I was about to be like, yo,
mira papa y de donde eres.
I didn't want to assume
that you speak Spanish too.
Because then, right?
A little racist, Hermano.
I'm not trying to be, you know, yo.
But anyway, the mission.
Follow me.
He's a robot, like, so...
How's that racist?
Okay, guys, check this out.
The coordinates you gave me
correspond to an old church.
Take a look.
That's Santo Domingo.
The Spanish built it on top of a Oinca temple.
Correcto. I picked up some
residual energy readings
around the courtyard, so I'm
guessing the key's somewhere close by.
But we may have
some trouble getting there.
Indiraimi, it's a festival
that shuts down the whole city.
Guess it's a night mission then.
No, Scourge could already be here.
We must retrieve
the other half before he does.
Me and Elena will do it.
Y'all never make it two blocks.
There's human security all around
the church. You'll never get through.
Then we'll have to take
a play out of your book.
We'll hide in plain sight.
We'll blend in with the parade.
It is not a bad idea.
We will keep an eye out for the Terracons.
Our first sign of trouble
we are going in.
Yo, Noah, think fast.
And if you need help just holler.
I am in position.
Alright, coast is clear.
Noah, Elena, it's go time.
Blend in. Act natural.
Autobots must be using
their new pets to reach the temple.
Lovely.
They're doing our work for us.
Go fetch.
Key's gotta be in here somewhere.
Yeah.
That stone work is 17th century.
What we're looking for
is something much, much older.
What is it?
It's the same insignia on Air Raiser.
But it's not lined up right.
Wait, you see that?
I think there's something under here.
There's another one.
Now where?
I thought it was...
It's some "Indiana Jones"-type shit.
You sure about this?
No.
Any sign of Scourge?
-Nope. All clear here.
Yeah, it's just groupies over here.
Stay on task, Mirage.
-Prime, you gotta learn how to relax, my man.
You know, you must be the first people
to walk here in half a millennium.
Yo, Sonic, you dead yet?
No.
Wait, did you just call me Sonic?
I think that's a temple.
What are we looking for?
You see the symbols on that temple?
The master wants a courtyard.
I think it's up there.
I think we found what we came here for.
I always wondered what
it would feel like to be there
when artifacts were actually found.
All right. Now come on, push.
Are you even pushing?
Yeah, I'm pushing.
Wait. Wait, what?
Just let me think.
Oh, no. Where is it?
Sometimes there's like
a false bottom or something.
Look, I think I found something.
You see these symbols?
I've seen markings like this.
The air raises statue of my museum.
They're new.
They're not on the trans-woke key.
There's two of them.
Raj.
Let's keep moving.
Just give me a second.
Run!
Go, go, go!
We got trouble! One of the things
is down here! Where are you guys?
Hang tight! I'm on the way!
The Autobots are moving.
They must have found the key.
Airazor, where are the humans?
The Underground, heading towards the jungle.
Aw, man! They're tailing us!
Do something! -You moving in too?
We had a gun this whole time.
Prime! What the hell are you doing?
I'm going to take that scourge's
key and then take off his head.
Guys!
I can use a little help!
Did someone call for backup?
Wait, wait, wait! -What?
Wait!
This is for me.
Come here.
Hold on.
I love your fire, Prime,
but you're going to die
on this speck of dust.
I can think of no
better place to bury you.
I will end your scourge.
That is a promise.
They're getting away.
Not this time.
I hear water.
Where are we?
What was that?
Who are you?
Why are you hunting for the key?
Yo Donkey Kong,
stay away from my friend.
Oh, Mariah.
Don't worry, your boy's got this.
Stranger danger, stranger danger!
Hey, hey, hey!
Not so fast!
Aye, aye, aye.
- Hey, over here, kitty kitty.
Stand down!
I won't ask a second time.
No! All of you, stop!
Arid!
Primal, I thought you were lost. All of you.
The others, are they?
I am all that is left.
Prime, these are my fellow Maximals.
Rhinox. Cheetor.
Sorry about scaring you, brother.
Scared? Please, I'm not scared.
That's just engine oil.
And our leader, Optimus Primal.
Optimus Primal?
Named after you,
the legendary warrior of Cybertron.
It's an honor.
Airazor, I'm happy to see you, old friend.
But bringing others here
was not part of our plan.
I fear you bring dark tidings.
Scourge has come to earth.
-He's found us.
And he has half of the key.
We must find the
second piece before he does.
But it wasn't in a cave. -It was.
But we moved it long ago to keep it safe.
-Where is it now?
Come with me.
That doesn't look so good.
When Skurge touches you,
he leaves a mark.
But I'll be all right.
Hey, back then you called me Sonic.
Yeah.
Your little bro's got this thing about
using real names over the airwaves, so...
You been talking to Chris?
He gave me this to keep tabs on you.
Make sure I'm keeping my promise.
Oh, here.
Next time, include warning labels.
Nah, go ahead.
Keep it.
I guess it does look better on me.
Just don't ask where
part of my body it came from.
So, who are you?
We Maximals are an advanced race, dedicated
to the expansion of life throughout the universe.
We use the Transwarp Key
to visit young worlds.
The Nazca Lines? The temple at Tikal?
That was you guys, right?
Not us. We cannot claim
credit for human ingenuity.
But you had the key.
Why stay on this world?
When Unicron destroyed our world, we took
an oath dedicated to the preservation of life.
No matter the cost.
And Earth has been a safe refuge.
This is Amaru.
He and his family are
the last descendants of a tribe
that has watched
over us for hundreds of years.
When we arrived,
they shared their world with us,
and together we protected its people
and our secret.
You allied with humans?
We did.
If you give us this key, tomorrow I will
light the beacon and bring Scourge to us.
The Maximals have already sacrificed
one home to protect the universe.
I won't risk losing another.
As a leader, I know you understand.
He is not the Optimus Prime I imagined.
Well, he has lost so much.
Many more will perish
if the key falls into the wrong hands.
If you had another chance to save
our home, would you act any differently?
Optimus, come. I want to show you something.
Your friend will find peace here.
This is raw energon.
The valley is rich with it.
Could this revive be?
I'm sorry, but in this state it is inert.
It will take a great power to ignite it.
Greater than anything we have here.
I see that you are surprised
we entrust the key to them.
Yes I am.
I've been amongst them a long time now.
There is more to them than meets the eye.
They are worth saving.
What if we didn't destroy you?
Maybe there's another way
to save both our homes.
Alaina, I made a lot of mistakes in my life.
This is different.
I can't fail at this.
I can't let my family down.
You're just like him.
You know that? -Who?
Optimus.
I'm serious.
He feels it too.
Feels what?
Like a beast of burden,
just trying to carry the weight
of the world on his shoulders.
You think he's some general
barking orders, but when I look at him,
all I see is a big brother
trying to protect his family.
Are you okay?
Who is it?
I can feel Scourge.
Kiss.
You're mine.
Run, Elena.
No!
Eraser.
They found us.
Everyone, defensive position.
Noah, guard the key.
Take Elena and find someplace safe to hide.
We must protect the humans.
Miss me?
Noah, Elena, get out of here!
We have to destroy it.
No.
Don't.
I know you want to protect your people.
But if you destroy that key,
our home will be lost forever.
We do not have to choose.
Please, Noah.
Elena!
Wait, wait, didn't I kill you already?
No, I'm the Maximal,
it's going to rip out your spark.
We'll see about that.
Kill them.
There is a note!
I can't hold it back
longer.
Find it, Airazor.
Remember our oath,
primal.
No matter the cost.
I can't hold it back!
Airazor, no!
Pramel!
I knew you could do this!
This is okay!
Do it!
Primal.
No matter the cost.
Alina, Alina, look at me.
Are you okay?
Scourge has the key.
Awaken, almighty Unicron.
Your time has come.
I'm sorry no.
We were looking out for your own.
I can't even be angry at you for that.
On my home world, we believe that
the battle with darkness will continue
till all are won.
I lost sight of that.
You fought for yours as I fought for mine, when
we should have been fighting the darkness together.
Well, I ain't done fighting yet.
All right, everybody, squad up.
Bring it in.
There's gotta be a way to stop this dude.
It's too late.
The transwarp has already been activated.
It has more energy than a supernova.
Any interruption will ignite it, like a bomb.
The only way to stop this process
is an access code you installed long ago
as a safeguard.
Okay, what's the code then?
The code was split along with a key.
Sadly, the second half of that code died with Air Razor.
No, wait, wait, wait. I got it.
The one hiding her half of the key,
it had markings in it.
Just like the ones I found
on the cave where you hid yours.
Together, they must
complete the access code.
So we got a chance now, right?
A slim chance.
That is all we need.
If you will show us the way, Primal.
Alright, we need to move quickly.
We have a small window before the portal
opens large enough for Unicron to enter.
The bridge is girded by a series of tunnels.
They are too small for Maximals, but...
But not for humans.
If Noah and Elena reach the central antenna,
they could use the code to shut it down,
remove the transwarp key, and close
the portal before Unicron enters our atmosphere.
But Scourge will be watching our every move.
He'll do anything to stop us from getting the key.
Then we bring the fight to him.
Autobots and Maximals
will charge the bridge together
and lure Scourge onto the battlefield.
While me and Elena
sneak it through the back way.
It sounds like we are going to die.
If we are to die,
then we will die fighting.
All as one.
This world is yours, master.
Scourge...
They're back.
Prime.
Protect the king.
Don't let them get to the bridge.
Maximals! Autobots! Roll out!
Rhinox! Tior! Maximize!
At least the foot soldiers took the bait.
-Yeah, but Skirt didn't.
He's guarding the key.
All right.
This should lead to the bottom
of the transwarp control panel.
Get the key, get the hell out of there.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna go distract Scourge.
You can't take on Scourge alone.
Relax.
I'm Mirage, remember?
Hey.
One, two, three, boom!
We gotta hurry up.
Take cover!
Get up!
Someone get me a real fight!
It's a fight you want?
You got one.
He was mine.
Nope.
Missed me.
No one gets any key, Maros.
What do we have here?
I let it go!
Brave, but futile.
Hey! Don't mess with my boy!
No one will remember this pathetic planet.
And no one will remember you.
Russ, what are you doing?
Keeping my promise.
Come on, you gotta get up!
It's okay, Noah.
Home, home team.
Haunty?
Ross?
Kill the other human.
Unicron, you fought bravely,
but this world is already mine.
What's so late?
Go!
Hey Nokos, you there?
You saw me.
Chris. -Noma?
What's going on?
Where's Marav?
He... he's gone.
Gone?
No.
I'm sorry, Chris.
I'm not gonna win this one.
We don't lose, right?
I wish that was true, but I can't.
Yes, you can.
No.
No, I'm not you.
I hate being sick.
Whenever I wanna give up,
you're always there telling me to keep going.
And now it's my turn.
Keep going, no?
You think you're nobody,
but you're the strongest guy I know.
You guys are so cute.
The bruh.
You're alive.
Yeah, but I'm gonna
need you to take the wheel.
You can do this.
You're my brother. Noah Diaz.
From Wilson Avenue.
Apartment 2C Brooklyn, New York.
No names over the airwaves.
Forget that.
Let them know who you are.
Yo scourge!
Remember me?
You think you can take me on alone?
He is not alone.
I'm not believing Brooke Lemmett.
Energon.
Frank!
Noah!
I'm getting really tired of you humans.
I got you.
You again.
You should have stayed dead!
I have come here to kick ass.
Glad to have you back.
Everyone, guard the bridge.
Elena, shut it down!
We gotta give her some cover!
We'll clear the way.
That's what I'm talking about.
Engine access code.
How hard could that be?
You've got to be kidding me.
Just you and me, Scourge.
Let's end this once and for all.
Master, the reinforcements.
Oh, man.
All right, I got this.
Let's go, B!
Say hallo to my little friend!
We gotta hurry!
That's right.
Yeah, you angry motherfucker!
You will never see
Unicron take this world!
You did it! Brooklyn baby!
No!
Unicron will prevail!
Elena!
I've had enough, Jeter!
Time to show you
the real power of the Prime!
This belongs to a friend of mine!
The panel is destroyed.
I can't stop it.
Autobots, Maximals, retreat to safety.
I will destroy the key myself.
Fine.
No.
There's got to be another way.
Bee, protect them.
Your sacrifice becomes our oath.
Thank you, my friends.
Pete!
We can't leave him out!
Everyone, find me!
Don't, prime.
I can give you everything you want.
Then you die!
Noah.
I got you.
Let me go, Noah.
Save yourself.
Till all are one.
Watch it, Brian!
Yeah baby!
Unicron. Is he dead?
Traps, but not dead.
Evil can never be
vanquished completely.
He could return.
Let him come. United,
we will destroy him once and for all.
I am Optimus Prime,
leader of the Autobots.
We have lost the Transwarp Key
and with it our ability to go home.
But we have gained an ally
in our battle against the forces of evil.
Forces too powerful for
any of us to defeat on our own.
But together we might just have a chance.
I am Noah Diaz.
What is there to know about me?
I was raised out in Brooklyn.
I got a little bro who calls me Sonic.
And if I gotta help save the universe
in order to save the people I love,
well then that's what I'm gonna do.
How you doing, sir?
You here for the job interview, Noah Diaz?
I'll tell him you're here.
This Sunday on 60 Minutes,
I sit down to talk with Elena Wallace.
She recently discovered
an underground temple
with a network of catacombs
dating back to 5000 BC.
I never could have
imagined making a discovery
of this significance.
So it's definitely a dream come true.
Brooklyn, baby.
They're ready for you.
-Thanks, sir. -Elevator in the back.
Why don't you tell me
about your strengths?
In addition to my
experience with electronics,
I've also been really developing
my team building skills too.
That's a... Look,
I'm gonna be honest with you.
Resume's a little thin.
Yeah, well, I just recently had a job.
Working internationally.
Oh, is that...
No, don't think it's on there.
No, it was a short-term contract.
Oh, well, that's cool.
Why don't you tell me about that?
It was in South America,
so I got to work on my Spanish.
But my mom was real happy about that.
You know moms, she's just me.
But while I was out there, honestly, man,
I was really just like, "Work, work, work, work."
That's a shame, 'cause I heard
the food is really good in Peru.
I didn't mention anything about Peru.
Well, that's where you were, right?
I was down in Cusco?
With you and Elena, and your...
I don't know, call 'em friends?
What's going on here?
We know a lot about you, Mr. Diaz.
Who are you, like the CIA or FBI?
We are a secret government organization,
strictly off the books.
We specialize in global threats,
planetary, loss prevention,
that kind of thing.
We're in the middle of an ongoing war,
and we'd love to have you join the fight.
You and your whole team.
You know... The big guys.
No idea what you're talking about.
That's a good answer.
All right.
Either way, I want you to know,
in lieu of the thanks
of a grateful nation,
we will be taking care
of your brother Chris's health care.
All of it.
From now on, he will have 24/7 access
to the greatest doctors in the world.
These are doctors who don't ask
their patients about account balances.
Are you serious?
You saved the world, kid.
It's the least we can do.
I don't know what to say.
-We'll work on that.
Your brother's gonna be just fine.
Oh, Chris was right, by the way.
No names over the airwaves.
We could really use someone like you, Noah.
Don't you think about it?
G.I. JOE
That oughta do it.
This? This is a complete waste
of your skills and my expertise.
Think it came out pretty good.
Well, I guess we could call it
modern art and sell it
to some cats in Soho.
No, I'm not selling. -What?
Why?
Is this about the five-o' thing?
No, I told you. I did not ditch you.
I was running to give it go.
I thought you knew the play.
All right, let's say I did ditch you,
even though I didn't.
Not for your sake I see your face. Let's just say
I did I think all the blood sweat and dead presidents
I put in to get in these car parts
for you make us even Steven. -It's not that.
This car is special.
This car is a jigsaw
puzzle made of garbage.
Hey, I bet the joint don't even start.
Bet.
Yo, Mirage!
Woo hoo hoo, yeah!
Your boy is back!
This dude said I wasn't even gonna start!
Sync and fixed by Neeboo